It's like the slogan says:
Le slogan dit:
"The physics is theoretical, but the fun is real."
"La physique est théorique, mais le plaisir réel."
We must not be playing it right.
On ne doit pas jouer comme il faut…
All right. Five. One, two, three, four, five.
Cinq. Un, deux, trois, quatre, cinq.
Oh, wow, look at that.
Hé, regardez!
My Department of Defense research grant is renewed.
La Défense renouvelle mes subventions.
...and build the large hadron collider.
et construire le grand collisionneur de hadrons !
You're a natural at this, Penny.
Tu as ça dans le sang, Penny.
And as the first beta testers, you two have quite the edge...
Vous êtes les premiers testeurs, vous aurez un avantage
...when we play with Wolowitz and Koothrappali on Sunday.
contre Wolowitz et Koothrappali dimanche.
Oh, gee, Sheldon, I don't think we can play on Sunday.
Sheldon, je crois que dimanche, ça ne va pas être possible.
Why not?
Pourquoi ?
Because of the reasons that Penny will now tell you. Penny?
A cause… des raisons que Penny va t‘énoncer. Penny ?
l have to pick up my friend Justin from the airport.
Je vais chercher Justin à l'aéroport.
There you go. She has to pick up her friend Justin.
Voilà, elle va chercher son ami Justin
And I can't play because I'm going with her. Right?
etje ne peux pas jouer. Je l‘accompagne.
He's got a lot of stuff, like guitars and amplifiers.
Il a pas mal de matos: guitares, amplis...
Wait. What are you talking about?
Attends... de qui tu parles, la ?
My friend Justin.
De Justin.
Pay attention, Leonard. That's why she can't play on Sunday.
Suis, un peu ! C‘est pour ça qu'elle ne jouera pas!
-Who is this Justin? -Your turn.
- Qui est Justin ? -Atoi!
-I told you about him. -Roll the dice.
- Je t'en ai parlé. - Le de !
Yeah. My friend from Omaha, plays the guitar.
Mais si. Mon ami guitariste d‘Omaha.
He's coming looking for session work.
Il cherche du boulot à L.A.,
So I told him he could crash on my couch.
donc je lui ai proposé mon canapé.
Come on. Roll a six, Penny dies horribly in a nuclear meltdown.
Allez ! Si tu fais 6, Penny va mourir à cause d‘une fusion nucléaire.
See what I mean when I say the fun is real?
Tu comprends “le plaisir est réel“, maintenant ?
Hang on. Some guy is gonna be sleeping on your couch?
Attends... Un type va dormir sur ton canapé ?
He's not some guy. He's my friend.
Pas un type, c‘est mon ami !
So by friend, do you mean "friend" friend...
Et par ami, tu veux dire juste ami,
...gay friend, or "ex-boyfriend you're now platonic with...
ami gay, ex-petit-ami-avec-qui-c'est-platonique-
...but still might have a thing for you" friend?
mais-qui-en-pince-encore-pour-toi ou…
Well, he's definitely not gay.
Il n‘est certainement pas gay!
Oh. A definitely-not-gay musician sleeping on my girlfriend's couch.
Un musicien certainement pas gay va dormir sur le canapé de ma copine...
Okay, we went out a little bit a long time ago.
On est sortis ensemble. Mais y a longtemps.
But we were never, like, going out.
On n'était pas vraiment ensemble.
Okay. Not to be pedantic, the last I checked...
Je veux pas la ramener, mais…
..."went out" was the past tense of "going out"...
”sortir ensemble", c‘est comme “être ensemble"
...which I think we all know is a popular euphemism...
et on sait tous que c‘est un euphémisme
...for saw each other naked.
pour dire qu'on s‘est vus nus.
I'll just roll for you.
Je lance le de pour toi.
You have a problem with Justin staying with me?
Ça t'embête que j'héberge Justin ?
What was your first clue?
Comment tu sais ?
Uh-oh. Industrial accident.
Accident industriel!
Know what? Don't talk to me like an idiot.
Ne me parle pas comme à une idiote.
I'm not talking to you like an idiot. I'm saying the whole idea is idiotic.
Ce n‘est pas le cas. Je dis juste que ton idée est idiote.
"You accidentally stare at a helium-argon laser. Lose one turn and a retina."
"Vous fixez trop un laser hélium-argon. Perdez un tour et une rétine."
How's that not talking to me like I'm an idiot?
Si, tu me prends pour une idiote!
It's my friend, it's my couch and it's my freaking life.
C‘est mon ami, mon canapé et ma vie, merde!
It's also your roll.
Et ton tour de jouer.
You know what? It is your life.
T'as raison, c‘est ta vie.
If you wanna have some stupid guitarist stay on your couch, fine!
Tu veux un guitariste sur ton canapé ? Vas—y !
Why don't you just rent bunk beds and invite the Black Eyed Peas?
Et prends des lits superposés pour les Black Eyed Peas!
Hey, if I wanna invite the line-up of Lollapalooza to my apartment, I will.
Si je voulais inviter la troupe de Riverdance chez moi, je le ferais!
It's none of your business.
Ça te regarde pas.
Do you know how childish you sound right now?
Tu t‘entends parler ? On dirait une gamine.
Oh, now I'm a child. Not an idiot anymore.
- Je suis une gamine, plus une idiote ? - Les deux ne sont pas incompatibles!
[BLENDER WHIRRING]
Qu‘est—ce qu'il fout, lui ?
Oh, and FYI. You never even heard of the Black Eyed Peas...
Oh, et au fait : les Black Eyed Peas, tu les as connus
...until you met me.
grâce à moi !
I heard of them.
J'en avais déjà entendu parler !
I didn't know they were a band.
Mais je savais pas qu‘ils faisaient de la musique.
Sheldon, she's gone. You can turn off the blender.
Sheldon, elle est partie, arrête le mixer.
Has your relationship reached its inevitable ugly end?
Est-ce que votre relation va indubitablement toucher à sa fin ?
No, we just had a little spat.
Non, c'estjuste une petite dispute.
Look on the bright side. As a result of Penny's forfeit...
Vois les choses du bon côté: Penny a déclaré forfait
...you have become the world's first winner of Research Lab.
et tu es donc le premier vainqueur au monde de Labo de recherche.
Would you like a commemorative snow cone?
Tu veux une petite glace pour fêter ça ?
I don't get how she can just announce...
Comment peut-elie m'annoncer
...that an old boyfriend is gonna sleep on her couch.
qu'un de ses ex dormira sur son canapé ?
Hey, I thought of a game we can play in the car.
Je sais à quel jeu on peutjouer en voiture.
I don't wanna play a game, Sheldon.
Je veux pas jouer.
It's called Scientists. Now, I will name three scientists...
Le jeu s‘appelle Scientifiques. Je vais donner 3 noms
...you'll put them in order of the size of their contribution to their fields.
et tu devras les classer selon leur contribution dans leur domaine.
To make this game even more compelling...
Pour pimenter le jeu,
...you must consider only the contribution of the man to the field...
tu ne tiendras compte que de leur contribution,
...not the validity of the field itself.
pas de l‘intérêt du domaine.
For example, Abu Musa Jabir ibn Hayyan...
Par exemple, Abu Musa Jabir ibn Hayyan
...made a greater contribution to the discredited field of alchemy...
a apporté davantage au domaine discrédité qu‘est l'alchimie
...than Halbert Vanderplatt made to neurobiology.
qu‘Halbert Vanderplatt àla neurobiologie.
Okay. Ready to have some fun?
Bien. Prêt à t'amuser ?
An old boyfriend who's "definitely not gay."
Un ex ”certainement pas gay"...
You know, that's what a guy likes to hear. "Definitely."
On aime tous entendre le : ”Certainement pas".
All right, I'll start with an easy one.
Bon, je commence par une facile:
And then I say one little thing and lend up being the bad guy.
Je dis juste un petit truc et c‘est moi, le méchant!
Hint. Madame Curie had her husband to help her.
Indice : Madame Curie était aidée par son mari.
What am I supposed to say?
Je devrais dire:
"Sure, Penny. I'm cool with your old boyfriend sleeping in your apartment."
"Pas de probléme, Penny, ça me dérange pas
Because I'm Penny, I'm pretty and I can do whatever I want."
moi, je suis lajolie Penny qui fait ce qu'elle veut."
[NORMAL VOICE] "You think you're doing me a favor...
“Tu penses me faire une faveur en sortant avec moi ?"
[MOCKING PENNY] "No. I'm doing you a favor by being in the same room as you."
“Je le fais rien qu'en étant dans la même pièce que toi !"
Leonard, stop the car.
Leonard, arrête-toi.
What?
Quoi ?
I can't listen to the two of you fight anymore.
J'en peux plus de vous entendre râler!
-Come on. We're late. -Calm down. We'll make the movie.
- On est en retard ! - On ne va pas rater le film.
I believe my alarm is appropriate. The movie starts in 17 minutes.
J'ai des raison de m'inquiéter, le film commence dans 17 minutes.
We'll need to make all the lights on Colorado Boulevard.
Les feux doivent être verts sur Colorado Blvd
Plus, skip the concession stand and pre-show urination.
et c‘est raté pour le pop-corn et le pipi préventif.
Oh, dude, I wish you had said something before I pounded that last Red Bull.
T'aurais dû dire ça avant que je finisse ma canette de Red Bull!
SHELDON: Go. Go, Power Rangers, go.
Go. Go, Power Rangers, go.
-We're, uh, going to the movies. -No, we're not.
- On va au ciné. - Faux,
We're standing in the hallway, suffering through an awkward encounter.
on est dans le couloir, face à une rencontre gênante.
Hang on.
Une minute.
They're showing a digital Time Bandits. You wouldn't wanna come, would you?
Ils ont remasterisé Bandits, bandits. Tu veux pas venir ?
Not really, no.
Pas vraiment, non.
All right. Invitation pointlessly offered, declined as expected.
Invitation inutile et logiquement déclinée,
Everyone's civil, nobody's fighting. Have a nice evening.
tout le monde est courtois, pas de dispute, bonne soirée.
Just give us a minute?
Vous pouvez nous laisser ?
Take all the time you need.
Prends tout ton temps.
So are we gonna talk about last night?
Est-ce qu'on va reparler d'hier soir ?
-Are you ready to apologize? -No.
- Tu es prêt à t‘excuser ? - Non.
Ehh! Wrong answer. But thank you for playing.
Mauvaise réponse. Mais merci d‘avoir participé.
Come on. This is stupid.
Arrête, c‘est idiot!
Oh, there it is again. You think I'm stupid.
Tu vois, tu crois que je suis idiote!
No. There's a difference between being and acting stupid.
Etre idiote et faire l‘idiote, c‘est différent.
Oh, yeah? Well, there's a difference between being ajerk and being an ass.
Y a aussi une différence entre être abruti et être un crétin !
No, there isn't. They're synonyms.
Non, c‘est faux. Ce sont des synonymes !
Well, that was rather unpleasant.
C‘était plutôt désagréable.
Yeah. I don't think I need my pre-show urination anymore.
Oui, plus besoin d‘aller aux toilettes avant le film.
Leonard, when that woman moved in three years ago...
Cette fille a emménagé il y a 3 ans,
...I told you not to talk to her. Now look, we are late for the movies.
je t‘avais dit de ne pas lui parler et voilà : en retard au ciné!
Hey, look Amazing Spider-Man 193.
Regarde ça : Amazing Spider—Man 193.
Got it.
Je l‘ai.
Remember this one? Spider-Man loses a big fight...
Tu te souviens ? Spider—man perd un combat
...and then his girlfriend breaks up with him.
et sa petite amie Ie largue.
You want me to get it for you? It will help take your mind off things.
Tu veux que je te l'achète ? Ça te changera les idées.
Hey, guys. What's going on?
Salut, les gars. Ça va ?
Ah, we need to kill a couple hours until the next showing.
On a 2 heures à tuer avant Bandits, bandits.
Oh, well, no problem.
Aucun problème.
l was thinking of closing early, and going home...
Je comptais fermer plus tôt et rentrer,
...but let's face it, that's just a smaller lonely room filled with comic books.
mais aprés tout, mon appart ressemble à ma boutique, en plus petit.
Thanks, Stuart.
Merci, Stuart.
Let me ask you.
A ton avis,
Do you think it's okay to have an ex-boyfriend sleep on her couch?
c‘est normal que Penny héberge son ex sur son canapé ?
-She's obviously way out of line. -Thank you.
- Non, elle va trop loin. - Merci.
But if she dumps you, she'll have a new boyfriend by tomorrow...
Mais si elle te largue, elle t'aura remplacé demain,
...and you'll have a new girlfriend when you figure out how to build one.
alors que toi, ta prochaine copine, tu devras Ia fabriquer!
So the only question is, how long until you fold?
La seule question, c‘est : quand vas-tu céder ?
lam not gonna fold.
Je ne céderai pas.
Well, excuse me. I don't think Penny's out of line. You don't own her.
Je ne trouve pas qu'elle aille trop loin. Elle ne t'appartient pas!
It's like my girl Beyoncé says:
Comme dit ma copine Beyoncé:
"If you like it, you should've put a ring on it."
“Si tu l'aimes, alors passe—lui la bague au doigt."
At the very least, when she found out Leonard was upset about it...
Quand elle a appris que ça énervait Leonard,
-...she should've backed off. -Like when a guy's upset...
- elle aurait pu annuler! - Un peu comme quand
...his friend agreed to take a class with him and then doesn't...
un pote vous lâche au cours de cuisine
...because he's doing ajuice fast with his mother?
pour aller boire des jus de fruits avec sa mère ?
I didn't know you were upset about that.
J'ignorais que ça t'avait énervé.
Really? Did you miss the subtle indicators?
Vraiment ? T'as pas saisi quand je t'ai dit : "Howard, je suis énervé" ?
HOWARD: Okay, sorry. -Maybe it's different in this country.
- C‘est bon, désolé. - C‘est différent, ici ?
Back in India, it means you're upset with a guy named Howard.
En Inde, c‘est clair: un type, Howard, m‘a énervé.
-I said I'm sorry. -Sorry doesn't make up for the fact...
- J'ai dit : désolé! - Il a fallu que je fasse
...I had to make chicken and rice with this vegan guy.
un poulet au riz avec un Végétarien !
Do you know what vegan chicken and rice is? Rice.
Tu sais ce que c'est, un poulet au riz avec un Végétarien ? Du riz!
You think I was having fun? Sitting around listening to my mother say:
Tu crois que ça m‘amusait d‘écouter ma mére dire toute la soirée:
[AS MRS. WOLOWITZ] "Have you ever peed so much in your life?"
”T‘as déjà pissé autant, toi ?"
Oh, my God. You are such a mama's boy.
C‘est pas vrai, t'es bien un fils à maman!
HOWARD: Don't bring my mother into this!
- Ne parle pas de ma mére ! - C‘est toi qui as commencé!
Stop it! Both of you!
Ça suffit ! Arrêtez !
This fighting, I might as well be back with my parents.
A vous entendre, on croirait mes parents :
[AS MOTHER] "I told you if you didn't quit drinking, I'd leave you."
“Je t‘avais prévenu, arrête de boire ou je pars."
[AS FATHER] "I guess that makes you a liar.
”T‘es une menteuse, alors. Je suis saoul et t'es toujours la !"
[AS MOTHER] "Stop yelling. You're making Sheldon cry."
"Ne crie pas, tu fais pleurer Sheldon."
[AS FATHER] "I'll tell you what's making Sheldon cry.
“Tu parles, il pleure parce que je t'ai laissé l‘appeler Sheldon !"
Boy, what got him so upset?
Pourquoi il est énervé comme ça ?
Oh, sure. You can tell when Sheldon's upset.
Sheldon, par contre, tu sais quand il est énervé!
Oh. Thank you very much. Come back soon.
Merci beaucoup! A bientôt...
With the other half of my tip.
avec l‘autre moitié de mon pourboire.
Hey, Sheldon. What're you doing here?
Salut, Sheldon. Qu‘est—ce que tu fais la ?
This is a restaurant. It's lunchtime.
C‘est un restaurant. Il est midi.
I'd think as a waitress you'd be familiar with the paradigm.
Ce paradigme devrait être familier aux serveuses.
-ls Leonard coming? -No.
- Leonard te rejoint ? - Non.
I believe Leonard is waiting for you to come back to him and apologize.
Je crois que Leonard attend que tu viennes t'excuser.
-Well, that's not gonna happen. -I assumed that.
- Ça n'arrivera pas. - J‘avais compris.
-Hence my true purpose in coming here. -Which is?
- D'où la raison de ma venue. - J'écoute ?
I want you to crawl back to him and apologize.
Tu dois revenir t‘excuser en rampant.
-l'm busy. -Excuse me, miss. I'd like to order lunch.
- Je suis occupée. - Excusez-moi, j'aimerais commander!
-Fine. What do you want? -I have a few questions.
- Trés bien. Tu veux quoi ? - Question :
First, I notice that you offer soup and a half sandwich.
vous proposez une soupe et un demi—sandwich.
-Yes. -Where exactly...
- Oui. - D'où Vient
...does the half-sandwich come from?
Ie demi—sandwich, exactement ?
Are you giving me half of someone else's sandwich?
De la moitié de quelqu'un d‘autre ?
Or do I have to wait for someone else to order the other half?
Ou bien il faut attendre qu'un client commande l‘autre moitié ?
No. Sheldon, they just make a half sandwich.
Non, Sheldon. On fait des demis.
You can't make a half sandwich.
Mais ça n'existe pas!
If it's not half of a whole sandwich, it's just a small sandwich.
Si c‘est pas la moitié d'un sandwich, c‘est un petit sandwich !
Okay, fine. It's soup and a small sandwich.
Si tu veux. Une soupe et un petit sandwich.
-ls that what you want? -Of course not. I'll have my usual.
- Tu commandes ça ? - Bien sûr que non. Comme d‘habitude.
-Great. -Aren't you gonna ask...
- Super. - Tu ne me demandes pas
-...if I want a beverage? -Usually lemonade?
- si je veux une boisson ? - Limonade ?
-Yes. -Want lemonade?
-Oui. - Tu veux ?
-Anything else?
- Oui. - Quoi d‘autre ?
Yes. I want you to apologize to Leonard.
Fais des excuses à Leonard !
lam not going to apologize. I've done nothing. He's overreacting.
Hors de question. Je n'ai rien fait de mai. Il en fait trop.
Irrelevant. The disruption in your relationship...
Aucune importance. Votre désaccord de couple rend ma vie intolérable.
Well, I'm sorry, Sheldon, but this really isn't about you.
Désolé, Sheldon, mais ce n‘est pas ton problème.
I don't follow.
Je ne comprends pas.
Yeah. Yeah, I'll be right there. Look, Sheldon, I have to go.
Oui, j'arrive ! Sheldon, je dois y aller.
All right. Let's assume ad arguendum, that in this case Leonard is wrong.
D‘accord. Mais supposons qu'ici, ad arguendum, Leonard ait tort.
-Leonard is wrong. -Considering the transgressions...
- Leonard a tort! - Tu vas souvent trop loin
...you committed that he's overlooked...
et il ferme souvent les yeux.
...don't you think that you could return the favor?
Tu pourrais pas t'excuser, juste une fois ?
I'm coming. Goodbye, Sheldon.
J'arrive ! Au revoir, Sheldon.
What do you mean transgressions I've committed?
Comment ça, je vais souvent trop loin ?
Were you under the impression that Leonard has no complaints about you?
Tu imagines que Leonard n‘ajamais à se plaindre de toi ?
Like what? Yeah, yeah, I see you.
Comment ça ? Oui, j'ai vu !
You're making a check sign in the air. Got it. Just hold your horses.
Vous me faites signe pour l‘addition. Une petite minuté.
-What does Leonard complain about? -Your driving.
- De quoi se plaint Leonard ? - De ta conduite,
The stuffed animals on your bed...
des peluches sur ton lit,
...that stare at him during your amorous activities.
du regard que tu lui lances pendant vos ébats amoureux,
Your constant tardiness, your singing.
de tes retards, de ton chant.
-My singing? -That's from my list.
- Mon chant ? - Ça, c‘est moi
Leonard'd be a fool if he didn't agree with it.
mais Leonard pense sûrement la même chose.
Okay, if Leonard has problems with me, why hasn't he just said so?
S'il a des reproches à me faire, pourquoi les cacher ?
According to him, you're over-sensitive and have a temper.
Selon lui, tu es trop sensible et susceptible.
Oh, really? Well, then do me a favor and tell Leonard that he can drop dead.
Vraiment ? Alors rends—moi service et dis à Leonard qu'il aille mourir!
And she wonders why she's constantly under-tipped.
Et elle s'étonne que ses clients soient avares en pourboire !
-Hey. -Oh, good, you're home.
- Salut. - Tu tombes bien.
-I need you to do me a favor. -Sure.
- Rends-moi un service. - O.K.
-Go apologize to Penny. -What?
- Va t‘excuser auprés de Penny. - Pardon ?
Right now would be good.
- Tout de suite, ce serait bien. - Leonard !
PENNY: Leonard! -A few minutes ago would've been better.
J'aurais préféré quelques minutes plus tôt.
I hear you don't like my stuffed animals, my driving or my punctuality.
Il parait que mes peluches, ma conduite et mes retards t‘insupportent.
Who would tell you something like that?
Qui t‘a dit une chose pareille ?
Why would you tell her
Pourquoi t'as dit une chose pareille ?
It doesn't matter why he told me. It's true, isn't it?
Peu importe pourquoi. C‘est vrai, non ?
Okay, yeah, it's true. But I can live with that stuff.
Oui, c‘est vrai. Mais je peux faire avec.
What I can't live with is you casually informing me...
Par contre, m'informer au dernier moment
...some guy is gonna be staying without asking me first.
qu'un ex va venir dormir sur ton canapé, ça, non !
That isn't even your problem. Problem is you don't trust me.
Le problème, c‘est que tu n'as pas confiance !
Oh, come on.
Admets-le...
Sheldon, have you ever once heard me say that I don't trust Penny?
Sheldon, tu m'as entendu dire que j‘avais pas confiance ?
Sheldon? Where did he go?
Sheldon ? Où est-il parti ?
Ugh. Your yelling must've freaked him out again.
Tes hurlements l‘ont sûrement effrayé.
Where are you going? You just walk away in the middle of an argument?
Où tu vas ? Tu t'éclipses au milieu d‘une dispute ?
No. I'm gonna find your roommate...
Je vais retrouver ton coloc
...before he hurts himself trying to cross the street or something.
avant qu'il ne se fasse écraser en traversant la rue.
Why didn't you say so?
Ben dis-Ie !
PENNY: Now I need your permission for that too?
J'ai besoin de ta permission ?
I can't read your mind, Penny.
Je ne suis pas télépathe !
PENNY: Really? Why not? You're so smart and I'm so dumb!
Oh, vraiment ? Pourtant, tu es intelligent et moi, idiote!
RAJESH: Stop knocking. It's open.
Arrête de frapper, c‘est ouvert.
Please tell my parents that our dark matter research...
Tu peux dire à mes parents que nos recherches
...is at a critical juncture. I can't come for my cousin Sanjay's wedding.
avancent et que je peux pas venir au mariage de mon cousin Sanjay ?
Ask our son what we're supposed to say to Mr. and Mrs. Chaudri...
Demande à notre fils ce que nous devons dire aux Chaudri
...whose daughter, Lakshmi, is flying in for the sole purpose of meeting him.
dont la fille Lakshmi rentre de Londres uniquement pour le voir.
I didn't ask you to set me up.
Je ne vous ai rien demandé!
-You should be thanking us. -Yes, Lakshmi got her stomach stapled.
- Remercie-nous ! - Oui. On lui a posé un anneau gastrique.
You have an opportunity to get in with her...
Séduis-Ia avant qu'elle ne maigrisse
...before she loses weight and her self-esteem goes up.
et qu'elle reprenne confiance en elle.
I don't care.
Je m'en fiche!
And why don't you think I can find a woman for myself?
Je peux trouver une fille tout seul!
You're 27, the closest thing we have...
Tu as 27 ans et pour l'instant,
to a daughter-in-Iaw is that Jewish boy, Howard.
notre belle—fille ressemble à un juif: Howard.
Oh, that is completely below the belt.
La, c‘est un coup bas !
Sheldon, tell my parents that Howard and l are just friends.
Sheldon, dis à mes parents qu'Howard n‘est qu'un ami!
Sheldon?
Sheldon ?
Howard and l are just friends.
Howard et moi sommes juste amis!
Fine. I'll come home for Sanjay's wedding.
Trés bien, je rentrerai pour le mariage de Sanjay.
What are you doing? He's not a lost dog.
Tu fais quoi, la ? On ne cherche pas un chien!
Hey, why don't you just let me find him...
Laisse—moi donc le chercher
...while you sit there hitting your imaginary brake?
et continue d‘appuyer sur ton frein imaginaire.
The brake might be imaginary, but that stop sign you just ran wasn't.
Le frein est imaginaire, mais pas le stop que tu as grillé.
-What stop sign? -Eyes on the road. Eyes on the road!
- Quel stop ? - Les yeux sur la route ! La route!
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Howard, answer the door! I'm busy!
Howard, va voir qui est la ! Je suis occupée!
HOWARD: I'm busy too! You answer it!
Moi aussi, je suis occupé! Vas-y, toi !
MRS. WOLOWITZ: I can't! I'm on the toilet!
Impossible, je suis aux toilettes!
HOWARD: God's sake, I don't need to hear that!
Pas besoin de préciser ! Tu peux pas juste dire que t'es occupée ?
MRS. WOLOWITZ: I said, "I'm busy," but that wasn't good enough for you!
C‘est ce que j'ai dit, mais ça te suffisait pas !
HOWARD: I hope it's one of those home invasion deals...
J'espère que c‘est pour un cambriolage
...and they shoot me in the head.
et que le cambrioleur me tuera !
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Well, if it's a home invader, don't tell them I'm on the toilet!
Si c‘est un cambrioleur, lui dis pas que je suis aux toilettes!
There's no one there.
Il n‘y a personne.
You're hearing things, you crazy old lady.
Tu perds la boule, Vieille folle!
Hey, Stuart. Have you seen Sheldon?
Salut, Stuart. T'as vu Sheldon ?
Yeah. He's, uh, over in the graphic novel section.
Oui. Il est au rayon des romans graphiques.
Built himself a little nest.
Il se construit un nid.
Thank you.
Merci.
-Uh, Penny. -Yeah?
- Penny... - Oui ?
-ls everything okay? -What do you mean?
- Tout va bien ? - Comment ça ?
Uh, Sheldon told me you and Leonard are having a fight.
Sheldon m‘a dit pour la dispute...
Oh, yeah, kind of. It's no big thing.
Oh, rien de grave.
STUART: Oh, good. Good.
Bien, tant mieux.
I love you.
Je t‘aime.
I'm not leaving until you talk to me.
Parle-moi, sinon je ne pars pas.
-Hey, what's going on? -lt's a little hard to explain.
- Qu‘y a-t-il ? - Difficile à expliquer.
He pretends he's in an alternate dimension...
Il prétend être dans une dimension parallèle
...that occupies the same physical space we're in, but he can't perceive us.
située dans le même espace que la nôtre, mais où il ne nous voit pas.
Don't flatter yourself. I'm just ignoring you.
Ne te donne pas trop d‘importance. Je t‘ignore, c‘est tout.
All right, come on, Sheldon, let's go home. We're done fighting.
Allez, Sheldon, rentrons. On a fini de se disputer.
I've heard that before.
C‘est ça, oui...
Then the next thing you know, I'm hiding in my bedroom...
Après, je finis caché dans ma chambre,
...blaring a Richard Feynman lecture, Mom shouting Jesus would forgive her...
à écouter une conférence de Feynman à fond, ma mére hurlant que Dieu
...if she put ground glass in my dad's meat loaf.
Ia pardonnerait si elle assassinait mon père
And my dad's on the roof skeet shooting her Franklin Mint collectible plates.
et mon père jouant au ball-trap avec les assiettes en porcelaine de ma mére.
Okay, there's gonna be no more shouting and no skeet shooting.
Il n‘y aura ni hurlements, ni ball-trap.
Really? Where's your friend Justin going to sleep?
C‘est vrai ? Et ton ami Justin, il dormira où ?
-Yeah, where is he gonna sleep? -Oh, my God, would you let this go?
- Oui, où dormira-t-il ? - C‘est pas vrai, tu vas arréter ?
I'd let it go.
Moi, j‘arrêterais.
Why should I let it go? Why don't you just tell the guy to find a place to sleep?
Pourquoi je devrais arréter ? Tu peux pas lui dire d‘aller ailleurs ?
Oh, for God sakes.
C‘est pas vrai...
So you have childhood issues.
Tu as eu une enfance difficile.
We all have childhood issues.
On a tous eu des problèmes.
At some point, you just need to grow up and get past them.
Mais un jour, il faut grandir et dépasser tout ça.
TOY: Fire. Fire.
Feu ! Feu !
Leonard, let me handle this. Please?
Leonard, laisse—moi m'en occuper.
-Fire, fire. -Look, let-- She--
- Feu ! Feu! - Ecoute, laisse…
Sheldon, please try and understand.
Sheldon, essaie de comprendre.
Look, Leonard and l are in a relationship and occasionally we're gonna fight.
Leonard et moi sommes un couple et parfois, il arrive qu'on se fâche.
But no matter what happens between us, we will always love you.
Mais quoi qu'il se passe entre nous, nous t'aimerons toujours.
Right, Leonard?
Pas vrai, Leonard ?
Always is a long time.
Toujours, c‘est long...
Sure. Always.
Bien sûr. Toujours.
You know, how about we buy you this robot and then we all go home?
Si on t'achetait ce robot et qu'on rentrait tous les 3 àla maison ?
I want that one.
Je veux celui—lè.
Okay, you can have that one.
D‘accord, on prend celui—lè.
Oh, come on. He's just gonna play with it twice...
C‘est pas vrai... Il va jouer deux fois avec
...and then it'll end up in his closet with all the otherjunk.
et il finira comme tous les autres, dans son placard.
Buy him the robot, Leonard.
Achète-lui, Leonard.
-Can I get this comic book too? -Yes, you can.
- Je peux prendre ce comic, aussi ? - Bien sûr.
We meet again.
Re-salut !
So, what did Justin say when you told him he couldn't sleep on your couch?
Qu'a dit Justin quand tu lui as dit d‘aller ailleurs ?
He's a musician. He'll sleep in his own vomit if he has to.
Il est musicien. Il dormirait dans son vomi s'il le fallait.
I should have asked for much more than a comic book and a robot.
J'aurais dû demander bien plus qu'un comic et un robot...
[ENGLISH - US - SDH]
[FRENCH]